Professional Summary

Programmer/data analyst with 8 years of experience primarily in the finance industry. Recent graduate of Tech Talent South's (TTS) coding bootcamp for web development. Completed TTS Next Level Rails course focused on test driven development and RESTful API's. Completed CPCC's Reach IT scholarship track for C# programming in 2015. On the job work experience with SQL, MS Office, and mainframe technologies. Self-directed learner continuously taking online IT-related courses in web technologies.

Technical Experience*/Training

- HTML5/CSS3/JavaScript*
- Ruby (Ruby on Rails)
- SQL*

- Test Driven Development
 WordPress
 (TDD) with RSPEC
- PHP
- C#

- COBOL/JCL/Easytrieve*
- MS Office*

Experience

Teaching Assistant

Tech Talent South

3/2017-5/2017

 Attending the full-time code immersion class to assist current students as needed while maintaining and improving my knowledge of the material covered

Data Analyst

Bank of America - Data Lineage and Data Quality Teams

7/2015-6/2016

 Metadata Management: Documented and certified data movement throughout the Mortgage, Card, Deposits, Payments and Student Lending domains. Documented lineage, data quality and controls to comply with regulatory compliance objectives.
 Utilized Excel, Access, SQL Server to perform analysis of metadata

Homemaker

South Charlotte Suburbs

10/2005-7/2015

- Created two new human beings and learned how to manage people with difficult personalities
- Managed household care, finances and earned the title of 'Budget Lady' by disgruntled family member shoppers

Data Analyst

Wachovia - Data Tools and Services Team

7/2002-10/2005

- QA Testing/Scripting/Ad Hoc Reporting: Utilized Easytrieve, JCL, WinRunner, ExcelVBA
 Test Director
- **Business analysis**: Requirements gathering and application enhancements to the Financial Center Information Directory (FCID)
- Project Management: Managed application update for FCID during interim period between project managers

Programmer Analyst

First Union - Credit Card Division

7/1999-7/2001

- Development: Wrote new applications and modified existing code utilizing COBOL, JCL, APS
- Production Support: Troubleshooted support issues on an on-call rotation
- **Business analysis**: Conducted code analysis to determine modifications needed for conversion of First Union's credit card application to MBNA

Keane, Inc. - Consultant

10/1997-6/1999

- Legacy Support Application Outsourcing Project (1-6/1999)
 - Business analysis: Gathered system documentation and worked with Ahold,Inc contractors to learn firm's legacy systems
 - o **Training**: Assisted in creation of orientation and training plans for new consultants placed on the project
 - Programming: Analyzed and maintained mainframe applications using COBOL and JCL
- Business Analyst for Year 2000 Software Upgrades (10-11/1998)
 - Examined Piedmont Natural Gas software inventory and conducted employee interviews to determine necessity of software applications
 - Researched Y2K compliancy of applications being retained beyond year 2000
 - Retrieved information from employee computers to complete either appropriate software upgrades or desktop software replacement
- Programmer Analyst for Year 2000 Remediation Project (10/1997-9/1998)
 - Converted VS/COBOL programs to COBOL II
 - Evaluated COBOL/CICS programs for year 2000 compliancy
 - o Conducted baseline, unit, and system tests for applications

Education

Post-Graduate Studies:

2016 - Tech Talent South – Attended 8-week code immersion course giving foundational base in HTML5, CSS3, Ruby/Ruby on Rails, and JavaScript. Completed 4-week follow-up course which focused primarily on test driven development with RSpec and API's.

2015 - CPCC - **Reach IT scholarship C# training** – A recession-driven government scholarship program to give qualified un- or under-employed IT workers an opportunity to learn a more current marketable technology along with career coaching. Three-month course gave foundational instruction in C#/.NET development.

University of North Carolina at Wilmington, B.A. Psychology